When creating documents, one of the
important factors to consider is that
once they have been created, you need to
evaluate the document and evaluate the use
of IT and the creation of the document.
So if you look at page three of session
six, and you scroll down, there are
a number of factors to consider.
So the first thing identified when
you look at your work, what are the
strengths and weaknesses of the work?
So you may be producing the document
that needs to be given to a client, or
it's used for a business meeting, and
you need to ensure that the document
is professional and meets the needs
of the audience and the organization.
So there's a variety of factors you need
to consider in relation to the strengths
and weaknesses and a number of those
are given on the slider on page three.
So if you have a look through
those and then look at the
work that you've produced.
So working through this unit, we've
created two PowerPoint presentations.
So if you look at those and evaluate those
in relation to these factors, so what are
the strengths and weaknesses of your work?
So once you've identified the
strengths and weaknesses of the
work, you then need to consider
ways that you can improve your work.
And as mentioned, on the slider above
there are a number of factors to consider.
But again, there are a number of factors
to consider how you can improve your work.
And this could be working
with other people.
It could be improving the training
in a specific piece of software,
getting further training if you're not
familiar with spreadsheets and Excel.
So it could be training specifically
tasked with improving your abilities
using that piece of software.
And then once you've done that, you also
need to look and review the outcomes
so the final outcomes of your document.
So the changes that you've made
before you can do anything with
it, you still need to review it.
So there's a variety of factors you
need to look at in the document.
And you need think about is the
quality of information, correct?
Having draft copies.
So, has that helped?
So if you prepare a document,
you create a draft copy before
you create the final version.
So that allows you to
identify any errors or issues.
And, but would having a draft copy help?
One of the things to remember is
if you're only creating a small
document or a small presentation, is
it worthwhile having a draft copy?
You also need to consider the
comparison to the original plan.
So you had a plan at the beginning,
so you've set out the steps that
you are going to follow and the
requirements for the document.
So has that met that plan?
Is the document meeting their needs?
So can you tick all of the boxes and
requirements relating to that document?
And checking with an audience.
So what I would do there is that
you would send it to a client.
You would send it to a colleague
and they could check to make sure
that everything was accurate and
it met the needs of the audience.
And you also need to consider the
effect of mistakes, so did you make
any mistakes during the task and
how have those mistakes impacted
on the final outcome of the task.
So all these things need to be considered
when you're producing documents.
It isn't just producing a document
and seeing right that's it, it's done.
You always need to evaluate it.
Especially when you're working in a
business environment, as the document
invariably has to look professional,
it will be presented to an audience,
whether that's an internal audience in
the organization or it could be clients
or customers for the organization and
not having a document that meets the
requirements could have a dramatic
impact on the impression that clients
and customers get of the organization.